dpdhl.jobs 2017-12-01

# Deutsche Post DHL Group | Data protection

**As of July 13, 2016**  
Deutsche Post AG (hereinafter called 'Deutsche Post DHL Group') is pleased that you have visited our website and are interested in our company, products and services. It is important to us to protect your personal data during handling throughout the entire business process. We want you to feel secure when you visit our Internet pages.

In the following, we explain what information Deutsche Post DHL Group collects when you visit our website and how this information is used.

### Personal data

Personal data is specific information about personal or factual characteristics relating to a certain natural person or a natural person who can be specified. This includes information such as your real name, address, telephone number and date of birth. Information that cannot be directly linked to your real identity - such as favorite websites or number of users of a site - is not considered personal data.

### Collection and processing of personal data

Deutsche Post DHL Group is committed to preserving the privacy of users of our website. When you visit our web pages, our web servers always temporarily save for security purposes the connection data of the computer connecting to our site, a list of the web pages that you visit within our site, the date and duration of your visit, the identification data of the type of browser and operation system used as well as the website through which you linked to our site. Additional personal information such as your name, address, telephone number or e-mail address is not collected unless you provide this data voluntarily, e.g. while completing an online contact form, as part of a registration, survey, competition, fulfillment of contract or an information request.

### Utilization and passing on of personal data

We use the personal data which you have made available to us exclusively for technical administration of the web pages and to fulfill your wishes and requests - thus primarily for fulfillment of a contract concluded with you or to answer your request.

Only when you have previously granted your approval or - if so stipulated by legal regulations - have not raised an objection do we also use this data for product-related surveys and marketing purposes.

Deutsche Post DHL Group does not share, sell, transfer or otherwise disseminate your personal data to third parties and will not do so in future, unless required by law, unless required for the purpose of the contract or unless you have given express consent to do so. For instance, it may be necessary to pass on your address and order data to our contractors when you order products.

### Information from the Group

The Deutsche Post DHL Group companies would like to contact you in order to provide you with the latest information about updates to our website or our offers, news, products and services. If you contact or register on our web pages, we sometimes request that you indicate whether or not you would like to receive direct advertising material from us. If you are already a customer of Deutsche Post DHL Group, you will naturally continue to receive necessary information about important changes in connection with existing contracts (e.g. rate changes).

### Use of web tracking

We use tracking software to determine how many users visit our website and how often. We do not use this software to collect individual personal data or individual IP addresses. The data are used solely in anonymous and summarized form for statistical purposes and for developing the website. It helps us improve the services we offer to you, and to make our website's content and services easier to use and more appropriate to you.

### Use of cookies

"Cookies" are small files that enable us to store information related to your PC and you, the user, specifically, while you visit one of our websites. Cookies help us to determine how frequently our internet pages are accessed as well as the number of users. And they help us configure our offers so that they are as convenient and efficient as possible for you.

On the one hand, we use what are called "session cookies", those that are stored exclusively for the duration of your visit to one of our internet pages. On the other, we use "persistent cookies" for retaining information about visitors who repeatedly access one of our internet pages. The purpose of using cookies is to be able to offer you optimal user guidance as well as to "recognize" you and thus be able to present (as much as possible) diversified internet pages and new contents during repeated use.   
**The content of a persistent cookie is limited to an identification number. Name, IP address, etc., are not saved. We do not create an individual profile of your online activities.**

### Cookie categories

Cookies can be categorized into 4 groups as follows: ****

  1. **Strictly Necessary:** These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for cannot be provided. ****
  2. **Performance:** These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how a website works. ****
  3. **Functionality:** These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features. For example, these cookies can be used to remember changes to text size, fonts and language. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymized and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites. ****
  4. **Targeting or Advertising:** These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests They are also used to limitthe number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers. The Deutsche Post DHL Group website does not currently use any targeting cookies.

**Deutsche Post DHL  Group table of cookies**

We have provided details of all cookies used on the Deutsche Post DHL Group website in the table below:

**Cookie**  
| **Name**  
| **Category  
see above  
** | **Purpose**  
| **More information   **  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
Adobe SiteCatalyst Analytics Cookies  
| s_cc, s_sq  
| Performance  
| 

The s_cc cookie is set when a visitor arrives at the homepage and read by JavaScript Code to determine if cookies are enabled. This is a session cookie and expires when the browser is closed.  

The s_sq cookie is set when a visitor arrives at the homepage. It collects information in an anonymous form on what links are clicked by the site visitor. By doing this, we can determine which links are used and which are not in order to improve our website.

It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve its websites and the user experience. This is a session cookie and expires when the browser is closed.  

| 

More info about cookies and privacy at Adobe  

More info about Adobe SiteCatalyst  

help pages for Adobe SiteCatalyst  

Adobe SiteCatalyst Analytics Cookie  
| s_vi  
| Performance  
| 

This cookie is set when a visitor arrives at the homepage. It is used to identify unique visitors and collects information on how our website is being used. We use this information to drive developments on our website and improve our ability to provide user-customized content. The cookie collects information in an anonymous form (unique visitor ID, time and date stamp).  

It is used confidentially only by DHL internally to improve its websites and the user experience. It expires after 90 days.  

| 

More info about cookies and privacy at Adobe   

More info about Adobe SiteCatalyst

help pages for Adobe SiteCatalyst  

Streaming Cookies  
|  bhCookieSess, bhResults

STST_BCNAME_<BCID>

STST_AUTH_<BCID>

STST_REG_CO_<COID>, STST_REG_CSO_<CSOID>, STST_REG_<BCID>

STST_STATS_SESSION_<BCID>, STST_STATS_STATUS_<BCID>

| 

Functionality / Strictly necessary

Functionality  

Functionality / Strictly necessary  
Functionality

Performance

| This combination of session and persistent first-party cookies deliver webcast and live streaming functionality to the Deutsche Post DHL Group website.  
Certain detection cookies are set as soon as a visitor arrives at a webcast page. These functional cookies detect the user’s device including the browser, OS (Operating System) and plug-in being used. Based on the results given, StreamStudio will provide streaming media that will work for the specific visitor.   
Functional cookies also store user preferences including registration. STST_REG_CO_<COID>, STST_REG_CSO_<CSOID>, STST_REG_<BCID> do not have an expiry date, STST_AUTH_<BCID> expires after 24 hours and any other functional cookies expire at the end of the current session.  
Performance cookies collect analytical data for Deutsche Post DHL Group to understand how visitors use and view webcasts. For example, we can see which webcasts are most popular, identify which webcasts have been watched the most etc. Cookies allow web analytics services to recognize your browser or device and, for example, identify whether you have visited our streaming services before. The information is anonymous and only used for statistical purposes.  
Analytics are used confidentially only by Deutsche Post DHL Group internally to improve its websites and the user experience and the cookies expire at the end of the current session.  
_Please note that StreamStudio webcasts will not work properly if cookies are turned off._  
| [More info about StreamStudio privacy  
](http://streamstudio.world-television.com/gaia/support/en/privacy.html "More Info about StreamStudio Privacy")  
Cart Cookie  
| dpdhl2011gb  
| Functionality / Strictly necessary  
| This first party session cookie provides a "shopping basket" functionality and is used predominantly in the Media and Investors areas of our website.   
For example, a user can choose various media files or press releases to save to a “Cart” and then download the consolidated selection. This is done using the available “Collect” links. The Cart Cookie is set when the user clicks the "Collect" link next to an item, storing the name and id of the selection.  
|    
Font Size Cookie  
| size  
| Functionality  
| This first party persistent cookie allows the user to change the font size on web pages and saves the desired numerical value.  
The cookie is set when the user clicks on either the "Font size" links provided at the top of each website page or the "Textsize" links provided in certain online documents.  
The cookie expires 1 year after it is set.  
|    
Online Survey Cookie  
| dpost_survey  
| Functionality  
| This cookie is set to support the technical control of our online customer survey.   
The survey cookie stores the number of invitations to the survey and completion of an interview issued to you for twelve months. The recording and readout of this information serves the sole purpose of not inviting you too frequently and not to survey you repeatedly.   
We do not store information you have provided for the survey in any cookie and no personal data is collected or transferred.  
| More info about cookies and privacy at WebXF Web Excellence Forum (PDF)  
  
Flash Cookies  
| LSO  
| Strictly necessary  
| Flash Cookies allow you to view Flash Player content and are independent of Deutsche Post DHL Group.  
Flash Player default settings do not seek user's permission to store cookies on local hard disk.   
If you wish, you can disable flash cookies (also referred to as 'local shared objects').  
| More info about how to manage or disable Flash cookies   
Full info on Flash Player functionality and related privacy settings  
  
YouTube Cookies  
| use_hitbox  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
| Performance  
| We embed videos using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. Some of these videos are from our official YouTube channel.  
This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. | To find out more, please visit YouTube's embedding videos information page  
Apply URL Cookie | Apstr

utmzSource

| Strictly necessary  
Performance | Used for the job apply URL ending which consists of querystrings related to tracking.  
Custom source tracking for Apply URLs. The custom source is the referrering url, e.g. Google, Yahoo, or TalentBrew. | More info about TalentBrew privacy  
Viewed Jobs Cookie | 

viewedJobs

savedViewedJobs

| Strictly necessary | Contains job and client id of what job a user viewed or marked as ‘saved’. This is used on DPDHL.jobs for the Recently Viewed Jobs Module. |    
Search **** Form **** Cookie | searchFormCookie | Strictly necessary | Used for storing users last location they have selected to search for jobs. |    
  
### Sharing tools: third party cookies

Deutsche Post DHL Group offers social bookmarks at the bottom of every page. These make it easy for visitors to bookmark and share content through their favorite social networks. If you decide to share content, cookies may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. Deutsche Post DHL Group does not control the use of these cookies and you should therefore check the relevant third party's website for more information.

### Third party cookies in embedded content

Please note that on some pages of our websites you may notice that cookies have been set that are not related to Deutsche Post DHL Group. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Vimeo, these service providers may set their own cookies on your web browser. Deutsche Post DHL Group does not control the use of these cookies and cannot access them due to the way that cookies work, as cookies can only be accessed by the party who originally set them. You should check the third party websites for more information about these cookies.

### How to manage cookies

Using our products and services without cookies is also possible. In your browser, you can deactivate the saving of cookies, limit them to particular websites, or set the browser to notify you when a cookie is sent. You can also delete cookies from your PC hard drive at any time (file: "cookies"). Please note that in this case you will have to expect a limited page presentation and limited user guidance. For example, our live streaming and webcasts may stop functioning correctly.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings.  
To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit: All About Cookies.

For further EU-specific advice on cookies and the various opt out options available to you, you can also visit the following website: Your Online Choices.

To opt out of being tracked by Adobe SiteCatalyst Analytics across all websites (or to reverse your setting if you have previously opted out), visit: Adobe SiteCatalyst Analytics Opt-out.  
Please remember that if you delete your cookies, or use a different browser or computer you will need to set your opt-out status again.

You can also choose to opt out of some or all of the advertising cookies set on your PC by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) website website").

Not everyone who visits our site will do so using a web browser. For example, some users will access the Deutsche Post DHL Group website or related applications using a mobile device. If so, it may not be possible to disable cookies or adjust web browser settings.

### Security

Deutsche Post DHL Group takes all of the necessary technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data from being lost or misused. For instance, your data is saved in a secure operating environment which is not accessible to the public. In certain cases, your personal data is encrypted by Secure Socket Layer technology (SSL) during transmission. This means that an approved encryption procedure is used for communication between your computer and the Deutsche Post DHL Group servers if your browser supports SSL.

Should you wish to contact Deutsche Post DHL Group by e-mail, we would like to point out that the confidentiality of the information sent cannot be guaranteed. The contents of e-mail messages can be read by third parties. We therefore recommend you send us confidential information only by post.

### Right to information

Upon written request, we will inform you what personal data (e.g. name, address) we have saved on you.

### DPDHL Data Privacy Policy

The DPDHL Data Privacy Policy regulates the Group-wide standards for data processing with a special focus on so-called third country transfers, meaning transfers of personal data to countries outside the EU, which do not have an adequate level of data protection. If you are interested in learning more about the DPDHL Data Privacy Policy, please use the following link:  
DPDHL Data Privacy Policy (Summary)")

### Changes to data protection statement

We keep our data protection statement under regular review.

Deutsche Post DHL Group reserves the right to change its data protection statement at any time with or without prior notice. Please check back frequently to be informed of any changes. By using the Deutsche Post DHL Group website, you agree to this Privacy Policy.

This statement was last updated on July 13, 2016.

### Contact

If you have questions in regard to the processing of your personal data, please contact the Deutsche Post AG data protection officer. We are also available to help with information requests, to take suggestions or to handle complaints.

Deutsche Post AG  
Data Protection Officer  
Gabriela Krader, LL.M.  
53250 Bonn  
Germany
